mylocalsalon.com 2018-06-11

# Privacy Statement - mylocalsalon

## Policies & Disclaimers

**Website Disclaimer**  
Whilst Shortcuts Software Inc. has made every effort to ensure the accuracy and currency of information provided on this site, Shortcuts Software Inc. does not warrant the accuracy and completeness of the material on this website and cannot accept any responsibility for errors or omissions. To the maximum extent permitted by law, Shortcuts Software Inc. provides you with this website on the basis that Shortcuts Software Inc. is not liable for loss, damage or liability arising from errors, omissions, inaccuracies or any misleading or out of date information whether contained on this site or any link attached to this site.

**Privacy Policy**  
Shortcuts Software Inc. is committed to protecting an individual’s privacy. This policy covers the personal information that Shortcuts Software Inc. holds and sets out the way in which Shortcuts Software Inc. will use, manage and protect personal information that comes into the possession of Shortcuts Software Inc. via the websites mylocalsalon.com, mylocalsalon.co.uk and mylocalsalon.com.au.

_Collecting and Using Personal Information_  
Shortcuts Software Inc. will only collect and use personal information that is necessary for its business purposes. All information collected is treated as confidential, and will only be used for the purpose for which it was supplied, unless permission has been obtained from the individual. Information will be collected by lawful, fair and unobtrusive means. Any sensitive information will be collected with the individual’s consent. 

_Disclosing Personal Information_  
Shortcuts Software Inc. will not disclose any personal information to any third party except with the consent of the individual or where required by law to do so. Shortcuts Software Inc. considers the act of an individual using the website to book an appointment as the individual's consent to disclose the individual's personal information to the third party receiving the booking.

_Retention and Disposal of Information_  
Shortcuts Software Inc. will only keep personal information it needs. Personal data will be retained for no longer than 2 years after non-use. Reasonable steps will be taken to remove or permanently de-identify personal information when it is no longer required.

_Accessing and Updating Personal Information and Right To Be Forgotten_  
Shortcuts Software Inc. will take reasonable steps to make sure that the personal information collected, used or disclosed is accurate, complete and up to date. Individuals may access and update their personal information at any time or notify us of any required correction. Individuals may assert their right to be forgotten at any time by accessing and deleting their account (via website) or by contacting Shortcuts Software Inc. and asserting their right to be forgotten to which Shortcuts Software Inc. will comply within 30 days.

_Data Security and Data Location_  
Shortcuts Software Inc. will take all reasonable steps to ensure all data collected is stored in a secure computer storage facility. Shortcuts Software Inc. uses Amazon Web Services in the United States to store all data collected.

**LINKS TO OTHER SITES**  
The Shortcuts Software Inc. website may contain links to other websites not maintained or related to Shortcuts Software Inc. These links are provided as a service to users and are not sponsored by or affiliated with this web site or Shortcuts Software Inc. Shortcuts Software Inc. has not reviewed any or all of the sites hyperlinked to or from this website and is not responsible for the content or privacy practices of other websites. The links are accessed at the user's own risk, and Shortcuts Software Inc. makes no representations or warranties about the content, completeness or accuracy of these links or the sites hyperlinked to this website. Websites that are accessible by hyperlinks from the Shortcuts Software Inc. website may use cookies. Shortcuts Software Inc. encourages you to read the privacy statements provided by other websites before you provide personally identifiable information to them. Shortcuts Software Inc. does not implicitly endorse third-party sites hyperlinked to this website.

**AUTOMATIC COLLECTION OF INFORMATION/COOKIES**  
The Shortcuts Software Inc. website's server, or the servers of companies that are used to operate this site, may place a "cookie" on your computer in order to allow you to use the website and to personalize your experience. A "cookie" is a small piece of data that can be sent by a web server to your computer, which then may be stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Cookies allow us to recognize your computer while you are on our website and help customize your online experience and make it more convenient for you. Cookies are also useful in allowing more efficient log-in for users, tracking transaction histories and preserving information between sessions. The information collected from cookies may also be used to improve the functionality of the website.

Most web browser applications (such as Microsoft Internet Explorer and Netscape Navigator) have features that can notify you when you receive a cookie or prevent cookies from being sent. If you disable cookies, however, you may not be able to use certain personalized functions of this website.

**INFORMATION COLLECTED AND HOW IT IS USED**  
We do collect personal information directly from individuals who volunteer to use some of our services. Collection of this information is required to deliver the specific services, but use of these services is voluntary.

If you do nothing during your visit to the website but browse or download information, we automatically collect and store the following information about your visit: 

  1. The Internet Protocol address and domain name used, but not the e-mail address. The Internet Protocol address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer. We use the Internet Protocol address to direct Internet traffic to you and generate statistics used in the management of this site; 
  2. The type of browser and operating system you used; 
  3. The date and time you visited this site; 
  4. The web pages or services you accessed at this site; 
  5. The website you visited prior to coming to this website; 
  6. The website you visit as you leave this website
